writingexplained.org 2019-05-23

# Privacy Policy - Writing Explained

Your privacy is important to me. Here are the details of how WritingExplained.org works, so you can protect yourself and your online privacy.

Different areas of the world now require different privacy disclosures. Therefore, it’s important to read the entire policy to make sure you completely understand our practices.

## I. If You Are Located in the EU

**A. What Personal Data Do We Collect From You?**

(1.) Opt-in to the Newsletter: Your name and email address.

(2.) Waiting Lists: Your name and email address.

(3.) Survey/Questionnaire forms: Your name, email address, submitted responses to questions about writing topics and interests.

(4.) Transaction: Your name, email address, billing information, and payment source.

**B. What is the Purpose of Processing Your Personal Data?**

We collect the information above for the following purposes.

(1.) Opt-in to the Newsletter: To provide you with updates via Writing Explained Newsletter.

(2.) Waiting Lists: Wait list subscribers join the Writing Explained Newsletter to receive general updates from Writing Explained and updates on particular courses or services.

(3.) Survey/Questionnaire forms: To understand what kind of content you are interested in, to answer questions you might have for us.

(4.) Transaction: To process a purchase you made with us.

**C. What Legal Basis Do We Have for Collection and Processing Your Information?**

Internet websites must have a legal basis for collecting information from individuals located in the European Union. Our legal basis for each of the ways we collect information from you is as follow. Also, please note that where consent forms the basis, you can withdraw consent at any time by opting out of any email message using the “unsubscribe” link.

(1.) Opt-in to the Newsletter: We will ask your consent first.

(2.) Waiting Lists: We will ask your consent first.

(3.) Survey/Questionnaire forms: We will ask your consent first.

(4.) Transaction: We will collect your information as part of a legal contractual transaction.

**D. Who Has Access to the Data We Collect?**

We process and access the data we collect from you. However, we use third parties to assist us with processing your personal data including the following categories of recipients:

  * Financial transaction processors (processing your payments)
  * Contest and survey platforms
  * Email communication manager
  * Marketing funnel providers
  * Website management services
  * Website design and programming services
  * Opt-in form providers
  * Social media websites

These third parties have signed contract with us in which they are prohibited from utilizing, sharing or retaining your personal data for any purpose other than we dictate.

**E. Cookies and Similar Technologies**

WritingExplained.org uses cookies to personalize your online experience. A cookie is a small text file saved by your web browser in order to make websites more interactive and accessible.

Cookies are widely used by websites and servers to provide many of the basic services we find online, but you can disable them in your browser menu if you wish.

Cookies cannot be used to deliver viruses and do not run programs on your computer.

**F. Your Right To Ask For Corrections, Erasure, And Export Of Your Data**

You have the right to control your personal data. Specifically, you have the following rights:

  * The right to be informed: We are informing you now with this policy.
  * The right of access: We’ll provide you with the data we have about you.
  * The right to rectification: Request we fix incorrect data about you.
  * The right to erasure: Request we erase certain data about you.
  * The right to restrict processing: Ask us to restrict certain type of processing of your personal information.
  * The right to data portability: Ask us to provide your personal data we have for export.
  * The right to object: Object to how we use your data.

To exercise any of these rights, please contact Jordan at support@writingexplained.org with your request.

**G. Your Right To Withdraw Consent**

Although this is mentioned above, we want to emphasize that wherever we’ve asked for your consent to collect or process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent.

If you receive email messages from us, you can use the “unsubscribe” link in each message to withdraw consent and completely stop the mailings.

**H. Privacy Concerns, Contacting Us, Complaints.**

You can contact Jordan Conrad at support@writingexplained.org with any request or question you have about these policies or your personal data.

## II. For Our Friends Regardless of Location

**A. Sale of Business**

Should we sell this site or our business, your personal information will be an asset transferred to the new owner.

**B. Writing Explained Newsletter**

The Writing Explained Newsletter is defined as any email, sequence of emails, promotion, or advertisement placement used to inform subscribers about writing, grammar tips, Writing Explained news, Writing Explained products, or other general information.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us.
